Parapsychology Laboratory Records, 1893-1984
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Parapsychology Laboratory; Rhine, J. B. (Joseph Banks), 1895-1980; Pratt, J. Gaither (Joseph Gaither), 1910-1979; Institute for Parapsychology Records, 1965-1980; Duke University. Psychology Department; Parapsychological Association; White, Rhea; Psychical Research Foundation; Pope, Dorothy; Rhine, Louisa E., 1891-1983; Sinclair, Upton, 1878-1968; McDougall, William, 1871-1938; Carrington, Hereward, 1880-1959; Murphy, Gardner, 1895-; Reiser, Oliver Leslie, 1895-1974; Weaver, Warren, 1894-; Stevenson, Ian.; Jastrow, Joseph, 1863-1944; Jung, C. G. (Carl Gustav), 1875-1961; Huxley, Aldous, 1894-1963; Huxley, Julian, 1887-1975; Margenau, Henry, 1901-; Mead, Margaret, 1901-1978; Journal of Parapsychology; Parapsychology -- Research; Extrasensory perception; Psychokinesis; Displacement (psychology); Research grants; Mediums; Spirits; Teachers
Related Material
Louisa E. Rhine Papers, 1890-1983
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Elizabeth A. McMahan Papers, 1926-2008
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Contents of Collection
- Background Files Series, 1970s-1980s, (1 box)
  Folders of historical and biographical information on the Parapsychology Laboratory and the Rhines. Includes some unprocessed material added to the collection, chiefly clippings and three journal articles on parapsychology and the Rhines (by McVaughn and Mauskopf, Matlock, and Zingrone and Alvarado).
  - Background files and other information, 1970s-1980s (Box 1A)
- Correspondence Series, 1893 and 1919-1984., 380 containers (190 lin. ft.)
  Personal and professional correspondence of J. B. Rhine along with correspondence of Parapsychology Laboratory staff members. The 1893 letter is a holograph letter from Richard Hodgson, Secretary of the American Society for Psychical Research, to William James. The 1919-1927 correspondence covers the period before Rhine came to Duke. From 1927 the correspondence reflects primarily Rhine's activities, but contains some letters written to and by other laboratory staff members. The last files include memorial letters written after the death of J. B. Rhine (1980). Includes subject files, research records, clippings, and photographs. Arranged chronologically, 1893-1936. Arranged chronologically by year, then alphabetically by correspondent in reverse chronological order, 1937-1984.
  - Correspondence, 1893, 1919-1926, (4 folders) (Box 1B)
  - Experimental Data, 1926 (Box 1B)
  - Weckesser Notes, 1926 (Box 1B)
  - Manuscripts, Literary and Philosophical, 1926-1927 (Box 1B)
  - Poetry and Songs, 1926-1935 (Box 1B)
  - 1927, January - December, (3 folders) (Box 2)
    - Wittenburg (Ohio) Conference (Box 2)
    - Harvard Research on “Margery”, (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Notes on psychical research (Box 2)
    - Rhine writings, (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - Talking animals (Box 2)
    - Thomas, John (Box 2)
  - 1928, January - December, (3 folders) (Box 3)
    - “Lady” (Box 3)
  - 1929, January - December, (2 folders)
    - Course Notes (Box 3)
    - Seminar on psychic research (Box 3)
  - 1930, January - December, (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - The Aetiology Of A “Psychical” Legend (Box 4)
  - 1931, January - December, (3 folders)
    - Bills and Finances (Box 4)
    - Notes and Writings (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - 1932, January- April (Box 4)
  - 1932, May - December, (4 folders) (Box 5)
    - Correspondence with students (Box 5)
    - Notes on statistical problems (Box 5)
    - Experimental Religion (Box 5)
  - 1933, January - December, (5 folders) (Box 5)
  - 1933, students, January - December, (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - 1934, January - July 15, (9 folders) (Box 6)
  - 1934, July 16- November 30, (9 folders) (Box 7)
  - 1934 Decemberand Undated, (3 folders) (Box 8)
    - Garrett Sittings (Box 8)
  - 1935, January - February 19, (4 folders) (Box 8)
  - 1935, February 20- March 18, (3 folders) (Box 9)
  - 1935, March 19 - June 26, (8 folders) (Box 10)
  - 1935, June 27 - August 31, (9 folders) (Box 11)
  - 1935, September 1- December 15, (9 folders) (Box 12)
  - 1935, December 16-31and Undated, (4 folders) (Box 13)
    - Manuscripts (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
    - Willoughby Papers (Box 13)
  - 1936, January 1- 28, (4 folders) (Box 14)
  - 1936, January 29- March 11, (8 folders) (Box 14)
  - 1936, March 12- April 24, (7 folders) (Box 15)
  - 1936, April 25- June 20, (8 folders) (Box 16)
  - 1936, June 21 - September 22, (8 folders) (Box 17)
  - 1936, September 23 - November 21, (8 folders) (Box 18)
  - 1936, November 22- December 30, (7 folders) (Box 19)
  - 1936,Undated, (2 folders) (Box 20)
    - Manuscripts (Box 20)
    - Testing Apparatus (Box 20)
  - 1937 (Box 21)
    - Aa - Az, (2 folders) (Box 21)
    - Allen, Irving B. (Box 21)
    - Atlantic Playing Card Co. (Box 21)
    - Ba - Bz, (3 folders) (Box 21)
    - Bryant, Paul (Box 21)
    - Bond, Esther (Box 21)
    - Boston Society for Psychic Research (Box 21)
    - Ca - Cz (Box 22)
    - Carpenter, Ray (Box 22)
    - Clark, C.C. (Box 22)
    - Crandall, Ella Phillips (Box 22)
    - Da - Dz, (2 folders) (Box 22)
    - Duke University (Box 22)
    - E (Box 22)
    - ESP In General (Box 22)
    - Experiences (Box 23)
    - Fa - Fz, (2 folders) (Box 23)
    - Farrar and Rhinehart, (2 folders) (Box 23)
    - Free, E.E. (Box 23)
    - Ga - Gz, (2 folders) (Box 23)
    - George, R. Wilfred (Box 24)
    - Gibson, Edmund Paul (Box 24)
    - Greenwood, Joseph A. (Box 24)
    - Ha - Hz, (3 folders) (Box 24)
    - Helman, “Genie”, (2 folders) (Box 24)
    - Huntington, Edward V. (Box 24)
    - I - J (Box 25)
    - Journal of Parapsychology, (2 folders) (Box 25)
    - K (Box 25)
    - Kaempffert, Waldemer (Box 25)
    - La - Lh (Box 25)
    - Li - Lz (Box 26)
    - Lists (Box 26)
    - Ma - Mz (Box 26)
    - McDonald, E.F. (Box 26)
    - McDougal, William (Box 27)
    - McFarland, J.D. (Box 27)
    - Manuscripts (Box 27)
    - Murphy, Gardner (Box 27)
    - N (Box 27)
    - No Reply (Box 27)
    - O (Box 27)
    - Ozanne, C. (Box 27)
    - Pa - Pz, (2 folders) (Box 27)
    - Pegram, Margaret (Box 28)
    - Pratt, Joseph Gaither (Box 28)
    - Q - Rz, (2 folders) (Box 28)
    - Rice, Hilton (Box 28)
    - Rumely, Edward A. (Box 28)
    - Sa - Ss, (2 folders) (Box 28)
    - ST - Sz (Box 29)
    - Sharp, Vernon (Box 29)
    - Shulman, Robert (Box 29)
    - Sinclair, Upton (Box 29)
    - Smith, Burke (Box 29)
    - Stuart, Charles E. (Box 29)
    - T (Box 29)
    - Thomas, John F. (Box 29)
    - U - V (Box 29)
    - Wa - Wg (Box 29)
    - Wh - Wz, (2 folders) (Box 30)
    - Warner, Lucien (Box 30)
    - Whitman Publishing Co. (Box 30)
    - Woodruff, Joseph L. (Box 30)
    - X - Z (Box 30)
    - Zirble, George and Sara (Box 30)
    - Zenith Radio Show, (2 folders) (Box 30)
  - 1937,Staff A - Z, (6 folders) (Box 31)
    - Staff, MacFarland, J.D. (Box 31)
    - Staff, Rhine, J.B. (Box 31)
  - 1938
    - Aa - Al (Box 31)
    - Am - Az (Box 32)
    - Abbot, C. (Box 32)
    - Ba - Bz, (5 folders) (Box 32)
    - Bond, Esther (Box 32)
    - Buck, G. (Box 32)
    - Ca - Cz, (4 folders) (Box 33)
    - Carpenter, C. Ray (Box 33)
    - Crumbough, Jane C. (Box 33)
    - Cox, Mrs. G.H. (Box 33)
    - Da - Dp, (3 folders) (Box 33)
    - Dr - Dz (Box 34)
    - E (Box 34)
    - ESP Test Machine (Box 34)
    - Fa - Fz, (3 folders) (Box 34)
    - Farrar and Rhinehart (Box 34)
    - Free, E.E. (Box 34)
    - Frick, Harvey L. (Box 34)
    - Ga - Gi (Box 34)
    - Gl - Gz, (3 folders) (Box 35)
    - George, R. Wilfred (Box 35)
    - Greville, Thomas N.E. (Box 35)
    - Ha - Hz, (4 folders) (Box 35)
    - Harding, Virginia (Box 35)
    - Huntington, E.V. (Box 35)
    - I - J, (2 folders) (Box 36)
    - Journal of Parapsychology, (2 folders) (Box 36)
    - Ka - Kz, (2 folders) (Box 36)
    - Kaempffert, Waldemar (Box 36)
    - Kirby, G. (Box 36)
    - La -Mz, (7 folders) (Box 37)
    - McDonald, E. (Box 37)
    - Martin, Dorothy (Box 37)
    - McFarland, J.D., (2 folders) (Box 38)
    - Manuscripts (Box 38)
    - Murphy, Gardner (Box 38)
    - N (Box 38)
    - No Reply (Box 38)
    - O (Box 38)
    - Ozanne, Charles E. (Box 38)
    - Pa - Pn (Box 38)
    - Po - Pz (Box 39)
    - Parapsychology Committee (Box 39)
    - Pre-publication Questionaire (Box 39)
    - Price, Peggy (Box 39)
    - Q - Rz, (3 folders) (Box 39)
    - Rothera, Ralph E. (Box 39)
    - Sa - Sj, (2 folders) (Box 39)
    - Sl - Sz, (3 folders) (Box 40)
    - Shulmen, Robert (Box 40)
    - Society for Psychical Research (Box 40)
    - Statements on ESP Needs (Box 40)
    - Subjects (experimental) (Box 40)
    - Suggestions (Box 40)
    - Symposium on ESP at Columbus (Box 40)
    - T - V, (3 folders) (Box 40)
    - Wa- Wz, (4 folders) (Box 41)
    - Warner, Lucien (Box 41)
    - Woodruff, Joseph L. (Box 41)
    - X - Z (Box 41)
    - Zenith Radio (Box 41)
    - Zirkle, George (Box 41)
  - 1938,Staff A - Z
    - Staff, Moore, Duncan (Box 41)
  - 1939
    - A (Box 41)
    - Aschaffenberg Handwriting Experiment (Box 42)
    - Ba - Dz, (8 folders) (Box 42)
    - Douglam, Ann (Box 42)
    - E (Box 43)
    - ESP After 60 Years: Correspondence with Critics (Box 43)
    - Experience (Box 43)
    - Fa - Fz, (2 folders) (Box 43)
    - Farrar and Rhinehart (Box 43)
    - Foster, A.A. (Box 43)
    - Ga - Gz, (2 folders) (Box 43)
    - George, Dr.R.W. (Box 43)
    - Goodfellow Telepathy Game (Box 43)
    - Graduate Research Council (Box 43)
    - Ha - Hz, (3 folders) (Box 44)
    - Holz, Arthur (Box 44)
    - Hopkins, Mary de Witt (Box 44)
    - Humphrey, Betty (Box 44)
    - Hutchinson, Lois (Box 44)
    - I - J (Box 44)
    - Journal of Parapsychology (Box 44)
    - Ka - Kz, (2 folders) (Box 44)
    - Kennedy, John L. (Box 44)
    - La - Lk (Box 44)
    - Li - Lz (Box 45)
    - Lists (Box 45)
    - Ma - Mz, (3 folders) (Box 45)
    - Marchesi, Karlo (Box 45)
    - MacFarland, James D. (Box 45)
    - Martin, Dorothy (Box 45)
    - Murphy, Gardner (Box 45)
    - N (Box 45)
    - No Reply (Box 45)
    - O (Box 45)
    - Ozanne, Charles E. (Box 46)
    - Pa - Pz, (2 folders) (Box 46)
    - Parapsychology Department (Box 46)
    - Q - Rz, (2 folders) (Box 46)
    - Russell, William (Box 46)
    - Sa - Ss (Box 46)
    - St - Sz (Box 47)
    - Siegel, Paul (Box 47)
    - Sisler, Ward (Box 47)
    - Slaughter, Maxine (Box 47)
    - Sloan, William (Box 47)
    - Stuart, Charles E. (Box 47)
    - Ta - Zz, (5 folders) (Box 47)
  - 1939,Staff A - Z (Box 48)
  - 1940
    - A - Cz, (7 folders) (Box 48)
    - Corington, W. Whately (Box 48)
    - Coffin, J.G. (Box 48)
    - Crumbaugh, Jones (Box 48)
    - D - E, (2 folders) (Box 49)
    - ESP Box Experiment (Box 49)
    - Experiences (Box 49)
    - Fa - Gz, (4 folders) (Box 49)
    - George, R. Wilfred (Box 49)
    - Ha - Hz, (2 folders) (Box 49)
    - Henry Halt and Co. (Box 49)
    - Handwriting Experiment (Box 50)
    - Holz, Arthur (Box 50)
    - Humphrey, Betty (Box 50)
    - I - J, (2 folders) (Box 50)
    - Journal of Parapsychology (Box 50)
    - Ka - L, (3 folders) (Box 50)
    - Life Article Letters, (2 folders) (Box 50)
    - Ma - Mz, (3 folders) (Box 51)
    - Murphy, Gardner (Box 51)
    - N (Box 51)
    - No Reply, (3 folders) (Box 51)
    - O (Box 51)
    - Ozanne, Charles E. (Box 52)
    - P (Box 52)
    - Parapsychology, Lab Brochure (Box 52)
    - Psychology Department (Box 52)
    - Q - Rz, (2 folders) (Box 52)
    - Russell, William (Box 52)
    - Sa - Sz, (3 folders) (Box 52)
    - Scientific Monthly Letters (Box 52)
    - Sloan, William (Box 53)
    - T - Zz, (4 folders) (Box 53)
  - 1940,Staff A - Z (Box 53)
  - 1941
    - A - Bz, (4 folders) (Box 53)
    - Ca - Cz, (2 folders) (Box 54)
    - Corington, W. Whately (Box 54)
    - D - F, (2 folders) (Box 54)
    - Flowers, Robert L. (Box 54)
    - Ga - Gz, (2 folders) (Box 54)
    - Germain, Walter M. (Box 54)
    - Gibson, Edmund P. (Box 54)
    - Ha - Mz, (9 folders) (Box 55)
    - Murphy, Gardner, (2 folders) (Box 56)
    - N (Box 56)
    - No Reply (Box 56)
    - O (Box 56)
    - Ozanne, Charles E. (Box 56)
    - P (Box 56)
    - Psychology Department (Box 56)
    - Q - R (Box 56)
    - Russell, William (Box 56)
    - Sa - Sn, (2 folders) (Box 56)
    - So - Sz (Box 57)
    - Snyder, Alice (Box 57)
    - T - Wz, (3 folders) (Box 57)
    - Woodruf, Joseph L. (Box 57)
    - X - Z (Box 57)
  - 1941,Staff A - Z (Box 57)
  - 1942
    - A (Box 57)
    - Ba - Hn, (10 folders) (Box 58)
    - Ho - Mz, (5 folders) (Box 59)
    - Murphy, Gardner (Box 59)
    - N (Box 59)
    - No Reply (Box 59)
    - O - R, (3 folders) (Box 59)
    - Sa - Zz, (5 folders) (Box 60)
  - 1942,Staff A - Z (Box 60)
  - 1943
    - A - Bh, (2 folders) (Box 60)
    - Bi - Cz, (4 folders) (Box 61)
    - Cox, Alice (Box 61)
    - Da - Ez, (2 folders) (Box 61)
    - Endowment Plan (Box 61)
    - F (Box 61)
    - Ga - L, (7 folders) (Box 62)
    - Ma - N, (4 folders) (Box 63)
    - No Reply (Box 63)
    - O (Box 63)
    - Ozanne, Charles E. (Box 63)
    - Pa - Ri, (3 folders) (Box 63)
    - Ro - Wg, (7 folders) (Box 64)
    - Wh - Zz (Box 65)
  - 1944
    - Aa - Bz, (5 folders) (Box 65)
    - Bentley, W. (Box 65)
    - Ca - Com (Box 65)
    - Con - Cz (Box 66)
    - Cornish, Louis (Box 66)
    - Da - Dz, (2 folders) (Box 66)
    - Dale, Laura Abbot (Box 66)
    - E - Grd, (5 folders) (Box 66)
    - Gre - Lz, (8 folders) (Box 67)
    - Ma - N, (4 folders) (Box 68)
    - No Reply (Box 68)
    - O (Box 68)
    - Ozanne, Charles E. (Box 68)
    - Pa - Pz, (2 folders) (Box 68)
    - Pratt, Joseph Gaither (Box 68)
    - Q - Rn (Box 68)
    - Ro - Rz (Box 69)
    - Russell, William (Box 69)
    - Sa - Sz, (5 folders) (Box 69)
    - Schmeidler, Gertrude (Box 70)
    - Stone, Candace (Box 70)
    - T (Box 70)
    - Tobey, Carl Payne (Box 70)
    - U - Z, (5 folders) (Box 70)
  - 1945
    - Aa - Aspr, (3 folders) (Box 70)
    - Ba - Bz, (3 folders) (Box 71)
    - Bently, W. (Box 71)
    - Ca - Dh, (4 folders) (Box 71)
    - Di - Gz, (6 folders) (Box 72)
    - Garrett, Eileen (Box 72)
    - Gibson, Edmund Paul (Box 72)
    - Greenwood, Joseph A. (Box 73)
    - Ha - Mz, (9 folders) (Box 73)
    - Murphy, Gardner (Box 74)
    - N (Box 74)
    - News Letters (Box 74)
    - No Reply (Box 74)
    - O (Box 74)
    - Ozanne, Charles E. (Box 74)
    - P (Box 74)
    - Piersol, Robert J. (Box 74)
    - Pratt, Joseph G. (Box 74)
    - Ra - Rz, (2 folders) (Box 74)
    - Russell, William (Box 74)
    - Sa - Wz, (8 folders) (Box 75)
    - Wenberg, Dorothy (Box 76)
    - X - Z (Box 76)
  - 1946
    - A (Box 76)
    - Autohypnosis (Box 76)
    - Ba - Bz, (3 folders) (Box 76)
    - Bentley, W.P. (Box 76)
    - Ca - Cn (Box 76)
    - Co - Gp, (7 folders) (Box 77)
    - Gr - Gz (Box 78)
    - Garrett, Eileen (Box 78)
    - Gibson, Edmund Paul (Box 78)
    - Ha - Ll, (6 folders) (Box 78)
    - Li - N, (6 folders) (Box 79)
    - No Reply (Box 79)
    - O (Box 79)
    - Ozanne, Charles E. (Box 79)
    - P (Box 80)
    - Psychology Department (Box 80)
    - Q - Sl, (4 folders) (Box 80)
    - Sm - V, (5 folders) (Box 81)
    - Wenberg, Dorothy (Box 81)
    - Wa - Wz, (2 folders) (Box 81)
    - X - Z (Box 82)
  - 1947
    - A - Bz, (3 folders) (Box 82)
    - Bentley, William P. (Box 82)
    - Ca - Dn, (3 folders) (Box 82)
    - Do - F, (3 folders) (Box 83)
    - Fleming, H. King (Box 83)
    - Form Letters (Box 83)
    - Ga - Jz, (5 folders) (Box 83)
    - K - Mz, (6 folders) (Box 84)
    - McConnell, Robert A. (Box 84)
    - N (Box 84)
    - O (Box 85)
    - Ozanne, Charles E. (Box 85)
    - Pa - Pz, (2 folders) (Box 85)
    - Pearson, Fred (Box 85)
    - Ra - Sb, (3 folders) (Box 85)
    - Sc - Sz (Box 86)
    - Sloane, William, (2 folders) (Box 86)
    - Ta - V, (3 folders) (Box 86)
    - Wa - Zz, (2 folders) (Box 87)
    - Pratt: Gibson, Edmund Paul (Box 87)
    - Pratt: Rhine, J.B. (Box 87)
  - 1948
    - Aa - Az, (3 folders) (Box 87)
    - American Society for Psychical Research (Box 87)
    - Asana, J. (Box 88)
    - Ba - Bz, (6 folders) (Box 88)
    - Ball, May (Box 89)
    - Benson, Stanley (Box 89)
    - Bentley, William Perry (Box 89)
    - Ca - Cz (Box 89)
    - Cornish, Louis G. (Box 89)
    - Da - Dz, (4 folders) (Box 90)
    - Dakota Weslyan University (Box 90)
    - Ea - Ez, (2 folders) (Box 90)
    - Fa - Fz, (3 folders) (Box 91)
    - Foreign Correspondence (Box 91)
    - Foundation for Integrated Education (Box 91)
    - Ga - Gz, (4 folders) (Box 91)
    - Ha - I, (6 folders) (Box 92)
    - Institute of Public Relations (Box 92)
    - Ja - Jz, (2 folders) (Box 92)
    - Ka - Kz, (3 folders) (Box 93)
    - Kearful, Jerome (Box 93)
    - La - Map, (4 folders) (Box 93)
    - Mar - Mz, (6 folders) (Box 94)
    - MacRobert, Russell G. (Box 94)
    - McConnell, Robert A. (Box 94)
    - McConnell, Robert A. (Box 95)
    - N - O, (2 folders) (Box 95)
    - Ozanne, Charles E., (2 folders) (Box 95)
    - Pa - Pn, (3 folders) (Box 95)
    - Po - Pz (Box 96)
    - Psychology Department (Box 96)
    - Q - Sch, (7 folders) (Box 96)
    - Sci - Sz, (6 folders) (Box 97)
    - Schaefer, Alice (Box 98)
    - Sloan, William (Box 98)
    - Society for Parapsychology (Washington), (2 folders) (Box 98)
    - Ta - Tz, (3 folders) (Box 98)
    - Tanagra, A. (Box 99)
    - Thouless, Robert A. (Box 99)
    - Toksuis, Signe (Box 99)
    - U (Box 99)
    - Urban, H.J. (Box 99)
    - V (Box 99)
    - Vasse, Christiane (Mrs. Pau) (Box 99)
    - Wa - Wim, (3 folders) (Box 99)
    - Win - Wz (Box 100)
    - White, Helen G. (Box 100)
    - Willys, L. (Box 100)
    - Walther, Gerda (Box 100)
    - X - Z (Box 100)
    - Pratt: Gibson, Edmund Paul (Box 100)
    - Pratt: Hatton, Bert (Box 100)
  - 1949
    - Aa - Az, (2 folders) (Box 100)
    - Administration (Box 101)
    - American Society for Psychical Research (Box 101)
    - Asana, J.J. (Box 101)
    - Ba - Bz, (5 folders) (Box 101)
    - Bayless, Raymond (Box 102)
    - Bentley, William Perry (Box 102)
    - Ca - Dh, (8 folders) (Box 102)
    - Di - Fz, (7 folders) (Box 103)
    - Foundation for Integrated Education (Box 104)
    - Ga - Gz, (3 folders) (Box 104)
    - Gibson, Edmund Paul (Box 104)
    - Ha - Har, (2 folders) (Box 104)
    - Has - Kim, (9 folders) (Box 105)
    - Ki - Map, (8 folders) (Box 106)
    - Mar - Mz, (4 folders) (Box 107)
    - McConnell, Robert A. (Box 107)
    - N - O, (2 folders) (Box 107)
    - Ozanne, Charles E. (Box 108)
    - Pa - Rd, (6 folders) (Box 108)
    - Re - Sh, (8 folders) (Box 109)
    - Si - Sz, (6 folders) (Box 110)
    - Society for Parapsychology (Box 110)
    - Sherman, Herold (Box 110)
    - Ta - Tz, (4 folders) (Box 111)
    - Thouless, Robert H. (Box 111)
    - U - Wg, (4 folders) (Box 111)
    - Wh - Z, (4 folders) (Box 112)
  - 1950
    - Aa - Az, (3 folders) (Box 112)
    - Administration (Box 112)
    - American Society for Psychical Research (Box 113)
    - Ba - Bz, (6 folders) (Box 113)
    - Bentley, William Perry (Box 113)
    - Bulletins (Box 113)
    - Ca - Ez, (9 folders) (Box 114)
    - Fa - Fz, (3 folders) (Box 115)
    - Foundations (Box 115)
    - Foundation for Integrated Education (Box 115)
    - Ga - Gz, (3 folders) (Box 115)
    - Gibson, Edmund P. (Box 115)
    - Ha - Haq (Box 115)
    - Har - Hz, (4 folders) (Box 116)
    - Hornaday, John (Box 116)
    - I - Kz, (3 folders) (Box 116)
    - La - Mn, (7 folders) (Box 117)
    - Mo - Mz, (2 folders) (Box 118)
    - McConnell, Robert A. (Box 118)
    - McElroy, W.A. (Box 118)
    - Na - O (Box 118)
    - Ozanne, Charles E. (Box 118)
    - Pa - Rz, (9 folders) (Box 119)
    - Rivers, Olivia (Box 120)
    - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 120)
    - Sa- Ss, (7 folders) (Box 120)
    - St - Sz (Box 121)
    - Society for Psychical Research (Box 121)
    - Ta - Tz, (4 folders) (Box 121)
    - Thomas, C.D. (Box 121)
    - Thouless, Robert M. (Box 121)
    - Translators (Box 121)
    - U - V, (2 folders) (Box 122)
    - Vasse, Christiane and Paul, (2 folders) (Box 122)
    - Wa - Wz, (5 folders) (Box 122)
    - X - Z (Box 123)
    - Pratt: Rhine, J.B. (Box 123)
  - 1950,Staff (Box 123)
  - 1951
    - Aa - Az, (2 folders) (Box 123)
    - Administration (Box 123)
    - American Society for Psychical Research (Box 123)
    - Ba - Bt, (4 folders) (Box 123)
    - Bu - Bz (Box 124)
    - Bentley, William P. (Box 124)
    - Burrelle's: Anps. (Box 124)
    - Ca - Dq, (8 folders) (Box 124)
    - Dr - Dz (Box 125)
    - Dog and Cat References (Box 125)
    - E - Fz, (4 folders) (Box 125)
    - Foundations (Box 125)
    - Foundation for Integrated Education (Box 125)
    - Ga - Haq, (3 folders) (Box 125)
    - Har - J, (7 folders) (Box 126)
    - Ka - Kz, (2 folders) (Box 127)
    - Knowles, Frederick W. (Box 127)
    - La - Mas, (5 folders) (Box 127)
    - Mat - Mz, (3 folders) (Box 128)
    - McConnell, Robert A. (Box 128)
    - Marches, Karlo (Box 128)
    - Na - O, (3 folders) (Box 128)
    - Ozanne, Charles E. (Box 129)
    - Pa - Pz, (3 folders) (Box 129)
    - Petree, Martha (Box 129)
    - Ra - Rz, (4 folders) (Box 129)
    - Rivers, Olivia (Box 130)
    - Roberts, Kenneth (Box 130)
    - Rose, Ronald (Box 130)
    - Sa - Sz, (6 folders) (Box 130)
    - Ta - V, (5 folders) (Box 131)
    - Vasse, Christiane and Paul (Box 131)
    - Wa - Wim, (3 folders) (Box 131)
    - Win - Z, (2 folders) (Box 132)
  - 1952
    - Aa - Az, (2 folders) (Box 132)
    - Administration (Box 132)
    - American Society for Psychical Research (Box 132)
    - American Weekly (Box 132)
    - Ba - Bi, (3 folders) (Box 132)
    - Bj - Bz, (3 folders) (Box 133)
    - Buck, Guy E. (Box 133)
    - Bentley, William Perry (Box 133)
    - Ca - Cz, (3 folders) (Box 133)
    - Da - Fz, (7 folders) (Box 134)
    - Filing Clues (Box 134)
    - Forwald, Haakon (Box 134)
    - Ga - Gn (Box 134)
    - Go - Hz, (6 folders) (Box 135)
    - Hart, Hornell (Box 135)
    - Ja - Jz, (2 folders) (Box 135)
    - Ka - Mas, (9 folders) (Box 136)
    - Mat - Pq, (8 folders) (Box 137)
    - Pr - Pz, (2 folders) (Box 138)
    - Parapsychology, Friends of (Box 138)
    - Ra - Ss, (8 folders) (Box 138)
    - Sta - Sz, (2 folders) (Box 139)
    - Sheffield, Fred and Kaufman S. (Box 139)
    - Ta - Tz, (2 folders) (Box 139)
    - Thouless, Robert H. (Box 139)
    - U - Waq, (3 folders) (Box 139)
    - War - Wz, (4 folders) (Box 140)
    - Warner Questionaire, (3 folders) (Box 140)
    - X - Z (Box 141)
  - 1953
    - A (Box 141)
    - Administration (Box 141)
    - American Society for Psychical Research (Box 141)
    - Ba - Bz, (3 folders) (Box 141)
    - Bentley, William Perry (Box 141)
    - Ca - Ch (Box 141)
    - Ci - Dz, (4 folders) (Box 142)
    - Dyne, L.G. (Box 142)
    - E - Fz, (3 folders) (Box 142)
    - Ga - Hz, (6 folders) (Box 143)
    - Hart, Hornell (Box 143)
    - I - Kh, (2 folders) (Box 143)
    - Ki - Mz, (9 folders) (Box 144)
    - N - Pz, (5 folders) (Box 145)
    - Parapsychology Foundation (Box 145)
    - Ra - Sh, (5 folders) (Box 145)
    - Si - Sz, (4 folders) (Box 146)
    - William Sloan Associates (Box 146)
    - Ta - Tz, (2 folders) (Box 146)
    - Thouless, Robert H. (Box 146)
    - U (Box 146)
    - V (Box 147)
    - Van Busschbach, J.G. (Box 147)
    - Wa - Z, (3 folders) (Box 147)
  - 1954
    - Aa - Az, (3 folders) (Box 147)
    - Administration (Box 147)
    - Ba - Bz, (6 folders) (Box 148)
    - Bentley, William Perry (Box 149)
    - Ca - Dn, (6 folders) (Box 149)
    - Do - Fz, (7 folders) (Box 150)
    - Frank, Walter A. (Box 150)
    - Ga - Gk (Box 150)
    - Gl - Hz, (7 folders) (Box 151)
    - Hart, Hornell (Box 151)
    - I - MacJ, (8 folders) (Box 152)
    - MacK - Nz, (7 folders) (Box 153)
    - News, Laboratory (Box 153)
    - O (Box 154)
    - O'Toole, Charles C. (Box 154)
    - Pa - Pz, (3 folders) (Box 154)
    - Parapsychology Foundation (Box 154)
    - Q - Rn, (2 folders) (Box 154)
    - Rob - Rz, (2 folders) (Box 155)